<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<update xmlns="http://ns.adobe.com/air/framework/update/description/1.0">
<version>3.1.6</version>
<url>http://dambots.com/games/dame/DAME.air</url>
<description><![CDATA[
DAME 3.1.6
- Added DAME.Log() command for exporters.
DAME 3.1.5
- Fixed sprite trails.
DAME 3.1.4
- Allow %frame% keyword to work in DAME.CreateTextForSpriteClasses to get the sprite previewIndex
DAME 3.1.3
- Paths can now be as large as you want.
- Paths can be filled in with a custom colour and alpha.
- Fix very large paths from crashing.
- Fix extremely large tilemaps zoomed out from being clipped incorrectly.

DAME 3.1.2
- Fix DAME crashing when you try to move tiles pasted in another group than the one they were copied from.
- Fix tilemap border being draw incorrectly when the map is zoomed out far in tile matrix mode.
- Option to force snapping of tilemap positions to units.
- Added help menu option to open settings file.
- Added Tool menu option to reset to default settings.
- Fix for crash when ignore map edges is ticked on a tile matrix with special connections.

DAME 3.1.1
- Duplicated sprite entries now copy all relevant data.
- Fix bug where loading a file with layer templates added duplicate entries.
- Added more options to control what can go in the settings file.
- Save sprites separately option has been moved to the Tools->Options window.
- Prevent the map height options from showing up on new map layers.
- Options will be reset upon loading a project saved before versions 3.1.0 and 3.1.1
- Can now add layer group templates.

DAME 3.1.0
- Added layer templates (for maps only).
- Added options in Tools->Options to impose restrictions on what can be done in a project (editing sprites/tilesets/only allow adding maps from templates...)
- Added option to enable frame editing of sprites (enabled by default as this was a pre-existing behaviour).
- Added option in sprites to lock rotation to 90 degree angles.
- Fix bug where links could be generated from an object to itself.
- Updated License for open source.
- Added some extra info to documentation.

DAME 3.0.4
- Fix crash when using image layers.
- Added ability to automatically keep anchors centered for sprites.

DAME 3.0.3
-------------
- Fixed bug with shared tile properties going out of sync.
- Added ability to create an enumerated custom filter type based on sprite names.
- Can now hide sprite class properties from instances and not export them if desired.
- Fixed problem with centered guide layer not being drawn correctly in some cases.
- Optimized grid rendering.
- Changing the current sprite entry while in selection mode now switches back to paint mode.

DAME 3.0.2
-------------
- Added menu option in view menu to restore lost popup and tool windows.
- Improved freehand and line drawing to remove antialiasing.
- Added ellipse shape tool when drawing on tiles.
- Fixed inability to draw on sprites.
- Fixed inability to change the sprite image index on each sprite.

DAME 3.0.1
-------------
- View Raw Image Data renamed to Edit Raw Image Data.
- Fixed bug the corrupts the image when raw image is edited.
- Added ability to crop or pad all the tiles in the raw image.
- Fixed inconsistencies with gridlines drawn on tilemaps with height.

DAME 3.0.0
-------------
Drawing:
- Can now draw shapes (lines,polygons,circles and boxes).
- New mode that will create new tiles as you draw.
- Sprite drawing improved, also with full select,move,copy,paste functions.
- Hold Spacebar to use eyedropper in draw mode.
- Revamped drawing toolbar.
- Can now flip selections in draw mode.
- Flood Fill in drawing mode can now use a tolerance value.
- Fixed Locked Tile Mode (when drawing on tiles).
- Can now insert/remove tiles(frames) from sprites in Draw Mode.
- Can insert new tiles under a selction.
- Improved drawing on isometric tiles.
Sprites:
- Added anims for anim sprites, editable on sprite info.
- Added shapes for anim sprites, allowing you to define custom named points, circles and boxes per frames.
- Added anim editor for anim sprites, accessible from the film strip icon in Draw Mode.
- Status bar now displays the name or class of the current selected sprte.
Paths:
- Added path events.
- Improved visibility of nodes on paths.
- Deleting the last node will now always delete that path.
Exporters:
- Updated flixel complex exporter to export SpriteInfo containing anim and shape data for all sprites.
- New parameter added for tile anims, which exports as %looped%
- Can add custom separators to various loops in exporters.
- Flixel complex exporter can now export sprite anims and sprite anim shapes.
- Added public (non static) boundsMin and boundsMax for each exported level in flixelComplex.
- Flixel Complex now automatically includes list of classes in BaseLevel for ClassReference dynamic spawning trick.
- Fixed bug with the %%if prop:%% not working.
- Added new xml data exporter.
- Can now use project specific exporters by placing lua files in your .dam project directory and using Menu:File->Export Using Project Exporter.
- Can specify file paths relative to the current project.
Tiles:
- Option to add only visible tiles to a tile matrix, allowing easier re-adding of already placed tiles.
- Improvements to the way tiles are rendered in lists.
- Option to make tile palette automatically scale tiles to fit width/height of pane.
- Ability to turn off the checkered pattern on the tile palette.
- The chosen answer from the prompt when exiting an unsaved tile matrix can be remembered.
- Indicators to help visualise the current stack height for tiles allowing z stacking.
Misc:
- New Icons!!! Thanks to Behzad Mohammad Rahimi Asad
- Can save the project to an image.
- Can now zoom out to 12% normal magnification.
- Added customisable property types.
- Tile matrices are now bound more tightly to tilesets.
- Fixed issues when removing tiles from a tilemap.
- Fix bugs with onion skin not being enforced.
- Right click menu option on layers or groups in the layers tree view to move them to the current location of the cursor.
- Moving groups with snap to grid enabled will now move them in steps of the tilemap size.
- Improved readability of tile lists in popup windows.
- Improved visibility of tilemap and selection borders when zoomed out.
- You can now specify properties on any layer type.
- Tile properties are now highlighted in the tilelist for easy navigation.
- Double click on entries in Layers and Sprites trees to edit their properties.
- Right click menu option to edit sprite entries within sprite editor.
- Added warning when starting a new file or loading a file from the desktop when there are unsaved changes in the current file.
- Fixed for graphical corruption at edge of screen with very large windows.
- Fixed incorrectly sized panels when starting DAME maximized.
- Game region overlay can now be centered on the screen.
- Extra gridlines sized based on the game region overlay size (overlay doesn't need to be active).
- Object links now drawn as arrows.
- Keyboard shortcuts for tile matrix and drawing modes.
- Select None will now deselect on all editor modes.
- Fix problems with images from imported DAME files in another location.
- Fix bug when swapping tiles referenced in multiple maps.
- Sprite entries will now display their classname in the tree view if no name is specified.
- Can now edit properties as multiline text via a menu option.



]]></description>
</update>
